<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Midway Driving School – ESL/Nervous Adult and Home School Behind the Wheel Driving Lessons Serving the Twin Cities (Saint Paul, Minneapolis), Duluth and Rochester]]></title><description><![CDATA[Midway Driving School - Driver education, tips, locations, rates, hours contact]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 23:17:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Help Decrease Traffic Jams by Using the Zipper Merge]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you are on a highway and there is a lane closure up ahead, it is best to use all lanes until you reach the closure. Do not merge early…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/help-decrease-traffic-jams-by-using-zipper-merge/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/help-decrease-traffic-jams-by-using-zipper-merge/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 17:04:08 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When you are on a highway and there is a lane closure up ahead, it is best to use all lanes until you reach the closure. Do not merge early! This adds to a traffic backup and can also lead to more accidents. Each car merge can be thought of as a separate intersection. Intersections slow things down. That’s why highways are so fast in general, there are on and off ramps but no intersections. When many cars decide to merge along different points on the same lane, this creates many mini-intersections, backing up both lanes of the highway. Instead, use all lanes and merge closer to the lane closure creating just one intersection. This method looks like a zipper, and so it is called the “zipper merge”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZcPby71TNC0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MnDot Zipper Merge Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dot.state.mn.us/zippermerge/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MnDot Zipper Merge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Well rested drivers get in far fewer accidents]]></title><description><![CDATA[Getting a good night’s sleep not only makes you feel better, but it can help you avoid a car accident. Drivers are at their best when they…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/well-rested-drivers-get-in-far/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/well-rested-drivers-get-in-far/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 16:42:38 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Getting a good night’s sleep not only makes you feel better, but it can help you avoid a car accident. Drivers are at their best when they have had at least 7 to 8 hours of sleep the night before, according to a recent report by the AAA Foundation for Traffic Safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;From the report, compared to drivers who got 7-8 hours of sleep a night:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6-7 hours had &lt;strong&gt;1.3 times&lt;/strong&gt; crash rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5-6 hours had &lt;strong&gt;1.9 times&lt;/strong&gt; the crash rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4-5 hours had &lt;strong&gt;4.3 times&lt;/strong&gt; the crash rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less than 4 hours had a &lt;strong&gt;11.5 times&lt;/strong&gt; the crash rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Read more:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aaafoundation.org/acute-sleep-deprivation-risk-motor-vehicle-crash-involvement/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Acute Sleep Deprivation and Crash Risk”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NPR Article, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2016/12/06/504448639/drivers-beware-crash-rate-spikes-with-every-hour-of-lost-sleep&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Drivers Beware: Crash Rate Spikes With Every Hour Of Lost Sleep”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Anxiety Reducing Breathing Techniques]]></title><description><![CDATA[Deep breathing exercises can help you reduce overall anxiety. MDS suggesting practicing these techniques at home to de-stress before driving…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/anxiety-reducing-breathing-techniques/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/anxiety-reducing-breathing-techniques/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 16:38:13 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Deep breathing exercises can help you reduce overall anxiety. MDS suggesting practicing these techniques at home to de-stress before driving. If you feel the need to practice deep breathing and you are driving, we suggest finding a safe and well-lit place to park your vehicle first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/2010/12/06/131734718/just-breathe-body-has-a-built-in-stress-reliever&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Just Breathe: Body Has A Built-In Stress Reliever&lt;/a&gt; - NPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://healthland.time.com/2012/10/08/6-breathing-exercises-to-relax-in-10-minutes-or-less/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;6 Breathing Exercises to Relax in 10 Minutes or Less&lt;/a&gt; - TIME&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/in-practice/201607/breathing-techniques-anxiety&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Breathing Techniques for Anxiety&lt;/a&gt; - Psychology Today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stay Back! - Tips for driving safely behind a snowplow]]></title><description><![CDATA[Winter driving means patience. Especially patience on icy roads and behind snowplows. Snowplows travel at slower speeds and have a limited…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/stay-back-tips-for-driving-safely-b/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/stay-back-tips-for-driving-safely-b/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 17:35:22 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Winter driving means patience. Especially patience on icy roads and behind snowplows. Snowplows travel at slower speeds and have a limited field of view. Make sure to be 5-10 car lengths behind one (according to MnDOT 10 is preferred). Also be prepared for a snowplow to exit/enter the highway frequently or even to cross over a median. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snowplows are here to make our roads safer! Let’s give them the room they need!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Read more winter tips from MnDOT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dot.state.mn.us/workzone/winter.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.dot.state.mn.us/workzone/winter.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Black Ice - Tips for driving safely on Minnesota's icy roads]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ice isn’t always visible on the roadway. When ice is hard to see we call it “Black Ice.” This can happen when precipitation falls and…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/black-ice-tips-for-driving-safely-on-m/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/black-ice-tips-for-driving-safely-on-m/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 17:34:22 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Ice isn’t always visible on the roadway. When ice is hard to see we call it “Black Ice.” This can happen when precipitation falls and freezes onto the cold pavement or a melt and freeze occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Black Ice and Icy road condition tips:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Slow down&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the speed limit, drive at a safe speed for icy roads. Go especially slow on bridges, overpasses, and tunnels. These may be icier than other parts of the road due to the air traveling above AND below the road. Also pay special attention to the road in the morning. The air warms faster than the pavement creating icier than expected road conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Give your car space, and avoid braking on the ice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is much harder to brake on ice, and ice may cause your car to skid. Make sure to give your car more room than you think you need between yourself and the vehicle in front of you. Also, turn off cruise control, so you are more actively engaged as a driver, and can give yourself more time to react and adjust as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Avoid distractions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you are ready to focus on the road with both hands on the wheel. Do not use your phone while driving. Texting while driving is both dangerous and illegal in Minnesota. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Read more about black ice from MnDOT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dot.state.mn.us/workzone/blackice.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.dot.state.mn.us/workzone/blackice.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Driving Tips for Construction Season]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ah yes, it is the magical time of summer in Minnesota. Time to enjoy the MN State Fair or a last trip to the cabin. Maybe 18 holes of…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/driving-tips-for-construction-season/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/driving-tips-for-construction-season/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:37:21 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Ah yes, it is the magical time of summer in Minnesota. Time to enjoy the MN State Fair or a last trip to the cabin. Maybe 18 holes of sunrise golf, or an evening picnic in your own backyard. However nice the weather is though, it is still construction season.  And this summer, we seem to have more than our fair share of road work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make use of these construction driving tips so you can spend more of your time enjoying the summertime rays and less of the summertime construction blues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Check Google first (before you get into the car!)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve driven this route a thousand times before, it is a good idea to check &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt; to see if  your route is taking longer than usual, or whether or not you need to select a new path to your destination. You can also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dot.state.mn.us/roadwork/current.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check MNDOT’s site for road closures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Give yourself extra time.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We speed and make poor decisions when we are hurried. Give yourself plenty of time this summer for the commute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Obey construction speed limits.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fines in construction zones are higher than on normal roadways. Err on the side of caution when it comes to speed in construction areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minimize distractions.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No multitasking on the road! Staying free of distractions helps you stay alert; so turn down the radio, keep your eyes on the road, and your hands on the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Give yourself, and the next car, plenty of space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving yourself more space between your car and the one in front of you, gives you more time to react to changes in speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More construction driving tips at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://safety.fhwa.dot.gov/wz/resources/fhwasa03012/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://safety.fhwa.dot.gov/wz/resources/fhwasa03012/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is “The Blind Spot?” And How Can I Manage It?]]></title><description><![CDATA[You’ve likely heard the term “blind spot” from other drivers, or a driving instructor. So what is it, exactly? Very simply, a blind spot is…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/what-is-the-blind-spot-and-how/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/what-is-the-blind-spot-and-how/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:17:59 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You’ve likely heard the term “blind spot” from other drivers, or a driving instructor. So what is it, exactly? Very simply, a blind spot is any spot on the road that isn’t visible to a driver under normal driving conditions. Usually, it refers to the spaces to the rear of either side of an automobile as its traveling forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how can we combat this potentially dangerous part of driving? Thankfully, the folks over at the &lt;a title=&quot;Car Talk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cartalk.com/content/avoiding-blind-spot-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CarTalk.com&lt;/a&gt; website created a great step-by-step procedure for helping to mitigate blind spots by adjusting your mirrors. We’ve posted the link below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember though, nothing replaces looking over your shoulder quickly before merging into another lane.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Winter Driving Tips]]></title><description><![CDATA[Minnesota winters are long and tough. But Minnesotans are tougher! We still maintain our daily routines of work travel, outdoor activities…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/winter-driving-tips/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/winter-driving-tips/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:14:17 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota winters are long and tough. But Minnesotans are tougher! We still maintain our daily routines of work travel, outdoor activities and socializing. We’re mobile in the winter! However, the bitter cold, heavy snowfall and rapid swings in temperature make driving especially difficult. Here are a number of helpful tips to keep in mind as you venture out onto the roads during the cold and snowy months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Make a Car Safety Kit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the Minnesota Department of Public Safety hundreds of Minnesotans become stranded on the road during bad winter weather. It is important to be ready for an unexpected delay due to a flat tire, car trouble or impassable conditions. Make sure your car has a dedicated place to store these items: jumper cables, a fleece blanket, a bottle of water, a flashlight, windshield scraper, a length of sturdy rope, a bag of sand, a first aid kit and, if space permits, a small shovel. It can also be helpful to place a few candy bars in your glove compartment, in case you’re really stranded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Take Your Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan to give yourself extra time on the road when you’re traveling during the winter. Accidents often occur when drivers are rushing to get to their location and push their driving ability past its limits. Peace of mind is worth those extra fifteen minutes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don’t Follow Too Closely&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great rule for every time you’re behind the wheel, but it’s doubly important during the winter. Because road conditions are unpredictable, give yourself an extra buffer between you and the car in front of you. A good rule for freeway driving is “the ten second rule.” When the car in front of you passes a sign, begin counting. If you pass the same sign before you reach the number ten, you’re following too closely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one can guarantee an accident-free winter of driving, but following these tips can go a long way towards improving your chances of having a safe winter on the road.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Minnesota Seatbelt Laws Save Lives]]></title><description><![CDATA[A few years ago, Minnesota lawmakers took a stand against belt-less drivers. For those special cases where one’s own well-being and safety…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/minnesota-seatbelt-laws-save-lives/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/minnesota-seatbelt-laws-save-lives/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 23:46:42 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, Minnesota lawmakers took a stand against belt-less drivers. For those special cases where one’s own well-being and safety isn’t a good enough reason to buckle up, now police officers are empowered to pull over Minnesota drivers for the sole purpose of issuing tickets to otherwise law-abiding drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did their belt-buckling and life-saving plan work? The short answer is yes. The long answer is yeeesssss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study done by the University of Minnesota shows that the new law resulted in a 68 fewer deaths and a whopping 320 fewer injuries between 2009 and 2011. That’s a lot of healthy and safe drivers that might not otherwise be on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the University of Minnesota study, check out this article from Minnesota Public Radio: &lt;a title=&quot;Minnesota Primary Seat Belt Law Study&quot; href=&quot;http://minnesota.publicradio.org/display/web/2012/03/26/minnesota-primary-seat-belt-law-study&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://minnesota.publicradio.org/display/web/2012/03/26/minnesota-primary-seat-belt-law-study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Summer Road Trip Planning]]></title><description><![CDATA[It finally happened. Summer FINALLY showed up in Minnesota. Summer in Minnesota means something different to everyone. For you it might mean…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/summer-road-trip-planning/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/summer-road-trip-planning/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 17:21:45 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It finally happened. Summer FINALLY showed up in Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summer in Minnesota means something different to everyone. For you it might mean outdoor barbeques, being eaten alive by mosquitoes, or summer road trips. Well, the bad news is you’re on your own for grilling tips and bug spray. The good news is that the good people at nhtsa.gov have assembled some useful &lt;a title=&quot;Summer Driving Tips&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nhtsa.gov/summer-driving-tips&quot;&gt;Summer Driving Tips&lt;/a&gt; to help you make your summer road trip a success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the key things for you to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Before you go&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing kills a road trip quite like car trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Road trips should be fun for everyone involved, but keep in mind that you’re really asking a lot out of your car. Make sure it’s ready to handle anything the trip throws at it. Tires, wiper blades, fluid levels, cooling systems, lights and air conditioners are great places to start to prevent any future car-related headaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not car-savvy, do yourself a favor and get your car checked out by a professional before you leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Safety First&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you followed the first step, your car should be happy and ready to go. Great job! Now, how about all those people inside the car? Yeah, they’re usually pretty important too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re traveling with children, make sure you’re fully aware of all the safety precautions that come along with that. For starters, small children should be in car seats, all children 13 and younger should be in the back seat, and EVERYONE, young and old, should be buckled up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you plan your route beforehand and don’t forget to schedule frequent breaks to keep yourself happy and alert, especially when travelling with children. If you’re traveling in a group with other adults, driving in shifts is a great way to reduce the burden of navigating a long road trip on any one person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, keep in mind that, being summer in Minnesota, it will more than likely be HOT. Make sure you’re prepared to deal with the heat and always be mindful of how quickly vehicles can heat up to dangerous temperatures in hot weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should plan for a safe and happy trip, but be prepared for the worst case scenario. A roadside emergency kit will be worth its weight in gold should anything go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On the Road&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you’re on the open road! Now that your road trip is underway, it’s important to be mindful of your surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to share the road. Summers, especially in Minnesota, mean more bicycles, more motorcycles, and more pedestrians. Keep everyone in mind when driving (especially those that may be harder to see).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, practice safe driving habits and stay alert. Don’t drive if you’re too tired. If you’re unsure, take a break. Especially when travelling with children, frequent breaks make the experience more pleasant for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In an Emergency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, darn. You got a flat tire. Now what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On any trip, you’re going to want to make sure you have a cell phone with you in case a call for help is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the roadside kit I mentioned earlier? I hope so. That’s going to come in handy now. Make sure to take all the safety precautions when doing any type of roadside repair. If you’re unsure whether or not you can handle a repair yourself, play it safe and call for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With smart planning and preparation, car troubles don’t need to derail your vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Most Importantly…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While following all the rules of the road and keeping you and your party safe, don’t forget to have FUN on your trip! It is a vacation after all!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is Defensive Driving?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Simply put, Defensive Driving is a way of avoiding accidents on the road. Defensive driving emphasizes cautious, smart, and calm driving…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/what-is-defensive-driving/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/what-is-defensive-driving/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 14:39:45 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Defensive Driving is a way of avoiding accidents on the road. Defensive driving emphasizes cautious, smart, and calm driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midway Driving School uses Defensive Driving techniques so that we can all share the road safely. Here are some links to learn more about Defensive Driving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;How Stuff Works - Defenseive Driving&quot; href=&quot;http://auto.howstuffworks.com/car-driving-safety/accidents-hazardous-conditions/defensive-driving.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How Stuff Works “How Defensive Driving Works”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Something as simple as putting on a seat belt could save your life in an accident; in fact, they save about 11,000 lives per year&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
-AOL Autos &quot;How To Drive Defensively&quot;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Take a Zen-like approach&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;US Department of Transportation &amp;quot;Defensive Driving&amp;quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fmcsa.dot.gov/safety/driver-safety/cmv-driving-tips-inadequate-surveillance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;U.S. Department of Transportation “Defensive Driving”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;The defensive driver tries to recognize potentially hazardous situations sufficiently in advance to allow time to safely maneuver past them.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to get a MN Drivers License if you are from another country (18+ with license from previous country)]]></title><description><![CDATA[For the DVS’s detailed description  &  fees for exams click here  To get your Minnesota Drivers License you’ll need… Proper identification…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/how-to-get-a-mn-drivers-license-if-you-afrnameountry-18-wlicense-from-previous/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/how-to-get-a-mn-drivers-license-if-you-afrnameountry-18-wlicense-from-previous/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 01:40:35 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dps.mn.gov/divisions/dvs/Pages/dvs-content-detail.aspx?pageID=551&amp;amp;pageTitle=Driver%27s%20License%20-%20Class%20D%20%E2%80%93%20New%20Resident&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;For the DVS’s detailed description &amp;#x26; fees for exams click here &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;To get your Minnesota Drivers License you’ll need…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Proper identification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you go to the DVS you will need to prove your identity and show proper paperwork each step of the way. &lt;a title=&quot;Identification Requirements&quot; href=&quot;https://dps.mn.gov/divisions/dvs/forms-documents/Documents/IdentificationRequirements_English.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Here is a list of what you may present to prove your identity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pass the Knowledge and Skills Tests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present white and yellow copy of your successful test results from the Knowledge and Skills Tests.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;** If you are from &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Virgin Islands&lt;/span&gt; and&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt; Guam,&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Canada&lt;/span&gt; you only need to take the Knowledge Test (written exam).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Previous Drivers License from Home Country&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New residents must show a drivers license or a certified copy of their driving record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pass a vision check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to have 20/40 vision in either or both eyes and peripheral vision of 105 in either or both eyes. If you wear glasses or contacts to drive you should wear these during this check and drivers Skills Test (road exam).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Have a photo taken&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pay appropriate fees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;New Resident Fees&quot; href=&quot;https://dps.mn.gov/divisions/dvs/Pages/dvs-content-detail.aspx?pageID=551&amp;amp;pageTitle=Driver%27s%20License%20-%20Class%20D%20%E2%80%93%20New%20Resident&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;You can find more information about fees here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pass Knowledge Test (written exam)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;DVS Locations&quot; href=&quot;https://dps.mn.gov/divisions/dvs/locations/Pages/default.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DVS Locations
&lt;/a&gt; Some locations offer a computerized test in English, Hmong, Vietnamese, Somali, Spanish and Russian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Minnesota Drivers Manual&quot; href=&quot;https://dps.mn.gov/divisions/dvs/forms-documents/Documents/Minnesota_Drivers_Manual.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drivers Manual&lt;/a&gt; This handbook will help you prepare for the test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passing this test allows you get an Instruction Permit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pass Skills Test (road exam)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show a Valid Instruction Permit &lt;a title=&quot;Instruction Permit FAQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://dps.mn.gov/divisions/dvs/forms-documents/Documents/InstructionPermitFAQ.pdf&quot;&gt;Instruction Permit FAQ&lt;/a&gt; (pdf)
In order to get an Instruction Permit you must pass the Knowledge test. Once you have the permit, if you don’t have a permit or license from another state or country, you will practice driving with an adult licensed driver for at least three months. Then you may take the Skills Test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functioning Vehicle &amp;#x26; Proof of Insurance. If you don’t have your own vehicle, Midway Driving School has cars to rent for your road skills test. &lt;a title=&quot;Contact MDS&quot; href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;Contact us today&lt;/a&gt; to set up your first behind-the-wheel lesson and to get information about using our cars for the Skills Test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Midway Driving School can help you!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Training Designed for ESL &amp;#x26; Nervous Adults&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one does it better! We have patient instructors that focus on your learning. Want to practice a specific skill? Let us know! &lt;a title=&quot;Locations and rates&quot; href=&quot;/locations-and-rates&quot;&gt;Set up that behind-the-wheel appointment today! &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Private Lessons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Midway, we care about giving you focused attention by focusing on private lessons. Less distractions in the car is better for your learning, confidence, and safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Free Pickup Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No wasted gas! We come and pick you up for your lesson. We have been serving the Twin Cities for over 30 years. &lt;a title=&quot;Locations and rates&quot; href=&quot;/locations-and-rates&quot;&gt;Take a look at our wide service locations.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Single Lessons or Discount Packages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy a 1 hour, 1 1/2 hour, or 2 hour lesson at a time or pay for 6 or 7 1/2 hour package deals and use when needed! Lessons are available from 7 A.M. until 8 P.M. Monday through Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cars Available for Minnesota License Road Test&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t have a vehicle for the big exam? Do not stress! We have cars available for Minnesota License Skills Test! After your first behind-the-wheel lesson you are eligible for renting one of MDS’s vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pay Special Attention at Intersections!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Drivers of all ages should pay special attention at intersections. And a recent study has proved it again. Taking your time to approach the…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/pay-special-attention-at-intersections/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/pay-special-attention-at-intersections/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 04:51:45 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Drivers of all ages should pay special attention at intersections. And a recent study has proved it again. Taking your time to approach the intersection slowly can calm a driver, but it can also mean less accidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;MPR Minneapolis Bike Car Crashes&quot; href=&quot;http://minnesota.publicradio.org/display/web/2013/01/15/news/minneapolis-bike-car-crashes&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; reports that bicyclists and drivers are equally to blame for accidents due to not yielding the right-of-way, and “The vast majority of crashes occurred within 50 feet of an intersection.” Minneapolis, has also been voted the “Top Bike-Friendly City” in the US. With bikes and cars sharing the road more and more, everyone needs to take their time and look, follow right-of-way, and show extra caution at the intersections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midway Driving School has offered nervous adult behind the wheel driving lessons for more than thirty years. &lt;strong&gt;No one knows better how to teach you to be a safe driver, and we’ll be with you every step of the way.&lt;/strong&gt; Give us a call and set up your first lesson today! Twin Cities (612) 623-4142 - Duluth (218) 626-0123 - Rochester (507) 289-3456&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Midway Driving School Difference]]></title><description><![CDATA[1. Convenient We work with your schedule. Driving lessons can be scheduled for Monday-Saturday. You also don’t need to waste time getting…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/the-midway-driving-school-difference/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/the-midway-driving-school-difference/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 22:27:38 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;1. Convenient&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We work with your schedule. Driving lessons can be scheduled for Monday-Saturday. You also don’t need to waste time getting dropped off or finding us, we come to you free of charge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Locations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we drive to you, we have been able to serve large areas of Minnesota. &lt;a href=&quot;/locations-rates&quot;&gt;See our full list of locations.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you are a homeschooling student, a nervous adult driver, or someone with English as a second language (ESL), we have patient and well-trained instructors that will give you the behind the wheel driving confidence you need. We’ve offered behind the wheel training in Minnesota for over 30 years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Call us today to set up your first driving appointment!&lt;/h3&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[“Share the Road” – MDOT Campaign to See Pedestrians]]></title><description><![CDATA[According to the  Star Tribune , pedestrian deaths in 2012 are already at a 5 year high in Minnesota. MDot has decided to launch a  “Share…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/share-the-road/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/share-the-road/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:59 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startribune.com/local/169120506.html?refer=y&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Star Tribune&lt;/a&gt;, pedestrian deaths in 2012 are already at a 5 year high in Minnesota. MDot has decided to launch a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dot.state.mn.us/peds/education/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Share the Road”&lt;/a&gt; campaign to raise awareness to this deadly, but very reversible trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here are some of their major tips:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Stop for pedestrians at crosswalks.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Watch for pedestrians at all times.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Avoid distracted and aggressive driving”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Midway Driving School, we make sure all our behind-the-wheel drivers understand the importance of safety while driving. Students are trained to actively pay attention to the road without distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MDS serves Saint Paul, Minneapolis, Duluth, Rochester areas. We also provide free pick-up for behind-the-wheel lessons. Midway driving school specializes in ESL, Nervous Adult, and Homeschool behind-the-wheel training. Our driver license service includes arranging appointments for our students to use our training cars for their Minnesota license Road Test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/locations-and-rates&quot;&gt;Click here to see if we serve your area and to make an appointment today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Tips for Nervous Adult Drivers and New Drivers]]></title><description><![CDATA[1. Make Sure Your Route Is All Planned Out Knowing where you are going helps a lot and makes you more confident in your driving abilities…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/5-tips-for-nervous-adult-drivers/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/5-tips-for-nervous-adult-drivers/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 23:35:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;1. Make Sure Your Route Is All Planned Out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing where you are going helps a lot and makes you more confident in your driving abilities. Just one thing less to worry about!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Take Breaks!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one is perfect and on long trips sometimes the driving conditions call for you to pull off to the shoulder or find a gas station. Take breaks when necessary! Maybe you’re tired, stressed, need to stretch your legs, or just need to get some food. Don’t feel bad doing it. Just compose yourself and then go back on the road when you are ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Remove Distractions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The less things vying for your attention the better your driving will be! General rule, keep your eyes on the road!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eat when your engine is turned off, not while driving.
Drive with as few passengers as possible.
Put your phone off to the side. No need for texting while driving!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Give Cars Extra Space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to drive a little slower, no problem! Make sure you’re in the far right lane and always give other cars ample space. Giving other cars extra space can give you a more time to make decisions and break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Practice Driving with a Trusted Friend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially for beginning drivers, make sure to only invite a trusted responsible friend into the vehicle. This person can catch mistakes, help navigate and make you feel at ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midway Driving School strives to make you feel comfortable while driving. &lt;a title=&quot;Midway Driving School Locations and Hours&quot; href=&quot;/locations-and-rates&quot;&gt;You can even schedule an appointment to focus on areas you personally want to work on to be confident on the road&lt;/a&gt;. Make and appointment today with MDS!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[MDS Welcomes Homeschool Students!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Not only does Midway Driving School specialize in nervous adult behind the wheel training, but also welcomes homeschool students who have…]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/mds-welcomes-homeschool-students/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/mds-welcomes-homeschool-students/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 17:10:10 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Not only does Midway Driving School specialize in nervous adult behind the wheel training, but also welcomes homeschool students who have taken their Minnesota classroom training online or at home. Just give us a call and we can arrange to provide you with the Blue Card necessary for obtaining your Instruction Permit. We will help your teen become a confident and safe driver. MDS serves most of the Twin Cities, Duluth and Rochester metro areas and even provides free pick-up in most areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Homeschool and Nervous Adult MDS Behind the Wheel Rates and Times&quot; href=&quot;/locations-and-rates&quot;&gt;Check your location and rates to set up your first appointment today!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Page! All Your FAQ Answered!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Check out our new  FAQ  page here! If you have further questions  Contact  us.]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/new-page-all-your-faq-answered/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/new-page-all-your-faq-answered/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 00:55:55 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Check out our new &lt;a title=&quot;Midway Driving School FAQ&quot; href=&quot;/faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; page here! If you have further questions &lt;a title=&quot;Midway Driving School&quot; href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt; us.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[November Special]]></title><description><![CDATA[Mention the  November web discount  when you call for $25 off your first lesson! Valid through the month of November only.]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/november-special/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/november-special/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 01:38:20 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Mention the &lt;strong&gt;November web discount&lt;/strong&gt; when you call for $25 off your first lesson! Valid through the month of November only.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Link to Minnesota Driver Manual]]></title><description><![CDATA[Click  here  for easy access the the Minnesota Driver Manual (pdf).]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/link-to-minnesota-driver-manual/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/link-to-minnesota-driver-manual/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 09:49:19 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://dps.mn.gov/divisions/dvs/forms-documents/Documents/Minnesota_Drivers_Manual.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for easy access the the Minnesota Driver Manual (pdf).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Website Discount!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Mention the  website discount  for $10 off your first lesson! See our locations and rates  here]]></description><link>https://midwaydrivingschools.com/website-discount/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://midwaydrivingschools.com/website-discount/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:46:14 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Mention the &lt;strong&gt;website discount&lt;/strong&gt; for $10 off your first lesson! See our locations and rates &lt;a href=&quot;/locations-and-rates&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>